# 04 Web APIs: Code Quiz

As you proceed in your career as a web developer, you will probably be asked to complete a coding assessment, which is typically a combination of multiple-choice questions and interactive challenges. Build a timed code quiz with multiple-choice questions. This app will run in the browser and feature dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by your JavaScript code. It will also feature a clean and polished user interface and be responsive, ensuring that it adapts to multiple screen sizes.

## User Story

```
AS A coding bootcamp student
I WANT to take a timed quiz on JavaScript fundamentals that stores high scores
SO THAT I can gauge my progress compared to my peers
```

## Acceptance Criteria

```
GIVEN I am taking a code quiz
WHEN I click the start button
THEN a timer starts and I am presented with a question
WHEN I answer a question
THEN I am presented with another question
WHEN I answer a question incorrectly
THEN time is subtracted from the clock
WHEN all questions are answered or the timer reaches 0
THEN the game is over
WHEN the game is over
THEN I can save my initials and score
```

The following animation demonstrates the application functionality:

![code quiz](./Assets/04-web-apis-homework-demo.gif)

### Review

You are required to submit the following for review:

* The URL of the functional, deployed application.

* The URL of the GitHub repository. Give the repository a unique name and include a README describing the project.

- - -
Â© 2019 Trilogy Education Services, a 2U, Inc. brand. All Rights Reserved.


Source: https://jsfiddle.net/anthkris/3fnzdnun/


questionsArray = [
    {
        questionText: "Commonly used data types DO NOT inlude:",
        answers: ["alerts", "booleans", "numbers", "strings"],
        answerId: 0
    },
    {
        questionText: "The condition in an if/else statement is enclosed within __________",
        answers: ["curly braces", "parenthesis", "quotes", "square brackets"],
        answerId: 1
    },
    {
        questionText: "Arrays in JavaScript can be used to store __________",
        answers: ["booleans", "numbers and strings", "other arrays", "all of the above"],
        answerId: 3
    },
    {
        questionText: "String values must be enclosed within __________ when being assigned to variables.",
        answers: ["commas", "curly braces", "quotes", "parenthesis"],
        answerId: 2
    },
    {
        questionText: "A very useful tool used during development and debugging for printing content to the degugger is:",
        answers: ["JavaScript", "terminal/bash", "for loops", "console.log"],
        answerId: 3
    }
]
:+1:
6
:heavy_check_mark:
1



var quizScore = document.querySelector("#counter");
var startButton = document.querySelector("#startButton");
var question = document.querySelector("#questionSpace")
var count = localStorage.getItem("count");


startButton.addEventListener("click", function(event){
    event.preventDefault();
    question.textContent = "questionsArray.questionText";
    question.setAttribute("class", type);



var questionGenerator;

startButton.addEventListener("click", function(event){
    document.write = "questionSpace";
});


var questionSet = [
    {
        questionText: "Commonly used data types DO NOT inlude:",
        answers: ["alerts", "booleans", "numbers", "strings"],
        answerId: 0
    },
    {
        questionText: "The condition in an if/else statement is enclosed within __________",
        answers: ["curly braces", "parenthesis", "quotes", "square brackets"],
        answerId: 1
    },
    {
        questionText: "Arrays in JavaScript can be used to store __________",
        answers: ["booleans", "numbers and strings", "other arrays", "all of the above"],
        answerId: 3
    },
    {
        questionText: "String values must be enclosed within __________ when being assigned to variables.",
        answers: ["commas", "curly braces", "quotes", "parenthesis"],
        answerId: 2
    },
    {
        questionText: "A very useful tool used during development and debugging for printing content to the degugger is:",
        answers: ["JavaScript", "terminal/bash", "for loops", "console.log"],
        answerId: 3
    }
]

// Inside, we latch onto the "emptyDiv" using the JavaScript ".getElementById" selector.
      var targetDiv = document.getElementById("empty-div");

      // We then use the JavaScript method ".textContent" to change the content to "Hello friends!"
      targetDiv.textContent = "Hello friends!";

      use 01 DOM Manipulation


              <p>Commonly used data types DO NOT inlude:</p>
        <label for="p1"><input type="radio" value="A"> alerts</label>
        <label for="p1"><input type="radio" value="B"> booleans</label>
        <label for="p1"><input type="radio" value="C"> numbers</label>
        <label for="p1"><input type="radio" value="D"> strings</label>
        <p>The condition in an if/else statement is enclosed within __________</p>
        <label for="p2"><input type="radio" value="A"> curly braces</label>
        <label for="p2"><input type="radio" value="B"> parenthesis</label>
        <label for="p2"><input type="radio" value="C"> quotes</label>
        <label for="p2"><input type="radio" value="D"> square brackets</label>
        <p>Arrays in JavaScript can be used to store __________</p>
        <label for="p3"><input type="radio" value="A"> booleans</label>
        <label for="p3"><input type="radio" value="B"> numbers and strings</label>
        <label for="p3"><input type="radio" value="C"> Answer C</label>
        <label for="p2"><input type="radio" value="D"> quotes</label>


</div>


<script>
    $(document).ready(function() {

        var questionSet = [
    {
        questionText: "",
        answers: ["alerts", "booleans", "numbers", "strings"],
        answerId: 0
    },
    {
        questionText: "The condition in an if/else statement is enclosed within __________",
        answers: ["curly braces", "parenthesis", "quotes", "square brackets"],
        answerId: 1
    },
    {
        questionText: "Arrays in JavaScript can be used to store __________",
        answers: ["booleans", "numbers and strings", "other arrays", "all of the above"],
        answerId: 3
    },
    {
        questionText: "String values must be enclosed within __________ when being assigned to variables.",
        answers: ["commas", "curly braces", "quotes", "parenthesis"],
        answerId: 2
    },
    {
        questionText: "A very useful tool used during development and debugging for printing content to the degugger is:",
        answers: ["JavaScript", "terminal/bash", "for loops", "console.log"],
        answerId: 3
    }
]

var myQuestions = [
	{
		question: "What is 10/2?",
		answers: {
			a: '3',
			b: '5',
			c: '115'
		},
		correctAnswer: 'b'
	},
	{
		question: "What is 30/3?",
		answers: {
			a: '3',
			b: '5',
			c: '10'
		},
		correctAnswer: 'c'
	}
];

	function showQuestions(questions, quizContainer){
        var output = [];
        var answers;

        for (var i=0; i<questions.length; i++) {
            answers = [];
            for (letter in questions[i].answers){
                answers.push(
                    '<label>'
                        + '<input type="radio" name="question'+i+'" value="'+letter+'">'
                        + letter + ': '
                        + questions[i].answers[letter]
                    + '</label>'
                );
            }
            output.push(
                '<div class="question">' + questions[i].question + '</div>'
                + '<div class="answers">' + answers.join('') + '</div>'
            );
        }
        
        }

	}

	function showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer){
		// code will go here
	}

	// show the questions
	showQuestions(questions, quizContainer);

	// when user clicks submit, show results
	submitButton.onclick = function(){
		showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer);
	}

    function showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer){
	
        // gather answer containers from our quiz
        var answerContainers = quizContainer.querySelectorAll('.answers');
        
        // keep track of user's answers
        var userAnswer = '';
        var numCorrect = 0;
        
        // for each question...
        for(var i=0; i<questions.length; i++){
    
            // find selected answer
            userAnswer = (answerContainers[i].querySelector('input[name=question'+i+']:checked')||{}).value;
            
            // if answer is correct
            if(userAnswer===questions[i].correctAnswer){
                // add to the number of correct answers
                numCorrect++;
                
                // color the answers green
                answerContainers[i].style.color = 'lightgreen';
            }
            // if answer is wrong or blank
            else{
                // color the answers red
                answerContainers[i].style.color = 'red';
            }
        }
    
        // show number of correct answers out of total
        resultsContainer.innerHTML = numCorrect + ' out of ' + questions.length;
    }

// on submit, show results
submitButton.onclick = function(){
	showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer);
}